A Guide to the Bowyer-Hubard Papers, 1767-1816 (bulk 1767-1782 )
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
Bowyer-Hubard Papers 1767-1816
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 1929.1
.
Correspondence and family papers of Michael Bowyer, (Captain of the 12th Virginia Regiment of the Continental Line,) of Augusta County, Virginia.
Bowyer, Michael.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1929
Biographical Information
Michael Bowyer of Augusta County, Va. was captain in the 12th Virginia regiment of the Continental Line. He married Frances Carpente r in 1766. Elizabeth Hubard, daughter of loy alist lawyer James Hubard married Michael Bowyer's son, John.
Scope and Content
Correspondence and family papers of Michael Bowyer, captain, Continental Line (12th Virginia regiment), of Augusta County, Virginia, including state commission as captain of Virginia militia (signed by Edm{un}d Pendleton, John Page, Tho{ma}s Lud{well} Lee, P{aul} Carrington, Dudley Digges, and J{ame}s Mercer) and continental commission (signed by {John Ha}ncock); certificate of leave to have family inoculated for smallpox (signed by Charles Scott); certificate of his marriage to Phreney {Frances ?} Carpenter in 1766: letters from John Page and James Wood containing military orders for Bowyer; agreement of Alexander McGrew to pay Bowyer; and letter from Lafayette introducing the French engineer, {Simon} Bernard. Also included is letter from James Murray; and letter from M{atthew or Meriwether} Hubard to Mrs. Frances Morton Hubard saying Lord Dunmore has advised him to accompany Lord Cornwallis to East Indies; bookplate of the Loyalist James Hubard; engraved plate for James Hubard's bookplate; and a framed silhouette of James Hubard.
Arrangement
N/A
Index Terms
Persons:
Bernard, Simon,1779-1839.; Bowyer, Frances Carpenter.; Bowyer, Michael.; Carrington, Paul,1733-1818.; Cornwallis, Charles Cornwallis,|cMarquis,1738-1805.; Digges, Dudley,1718-1790.; Dunmore, John Murray,|cEarl of,1732-1809.; Hancock, John,1737-1793.; Hubard, Frances Morton.; Hubard, James.; Hubard, Matthew.; Hubard, Meriwether.; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert Du Motier,|cmarquis de,1757-1834.; Lee, Thomas Ludwell,1730-1778.; McGrew, Alexander.; Mercer, James.; Murray, James.; Page, John,1744-1808.; Pendleton, Edmund,1721-1803.; Scott, Charles.; Wood, James,1741-1813.
Corporate Names:
United States. Continental Army - History.; United States. Continental Army. Virginia Regiment, 12th.
Subjects:
American loyalists - Virginia; Bookplates, American.; Smallpox - Vaccination - United States
Contents List
- Assorted Papers, Folder 1 of 1
  - James Murray, Norfolk, to Mrs. Hubard, Williamsburg, 17?? December 24.; 1
  - Certificate of 1766 marriage of M. Bowyer and Frances Carpenter, 1767 June 29.; 2
  - Commission by Virginia Committee of Safety to Michael Bowyer, Captain., 1775 Nov 11.; 3
    Printed form with manuscript insertions.
  - Commission by Congress to Michael Bowyer, Captain., 1776 Sep 20.; 4
    Printed form with manuscript insertion.
  - John Page, in Council, to Captain Michael Bowyer, Staunton, 1776 Nov 8.; 5
  - James Wood, Fort Pitt, to Michael Bowyer, Tiger's Valley, 1777 Mar 7.; 6
  - Indenture between M. Bowyer and Alexander McGrew, 1777 May 5.; 7
  - Leave of absence granted Bowyer by General Charles Scott, 1777 Nov 11.; 8
  - M[atthew] Hubard, London, to Mother, Williamsburg, 1782 Dec 30.; 9
  - Lafayette, LaGrange, France to [Michael Bowyer?], 1816 Sep 15.; 10
  - Bookplate of James Hubard, N.D.; 11
  - Copper engraving plate for bookplate of James Hubard, N.D.; 12
  - Framed silhouette of James Hubard, N.D.; 13